(619) 916-7464

Santee, CA

hayden.pour@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/hayden-h-pour

OBJECTIVE:

I am interested in Software Engineer position. My experience and interest in problem-solving, software development, Embedded systems, and application development enable me to support the software developer groups to increase productivity and to meet task requirements. Bringing excellent work ethic, infrastructure support, interpersonal skills, system analysis through various software development methodologies. This helps the company and the team to develop and build reliable and cohesive products.

EDUCATION:

MS in Robotics, University of California Riverside

B.S. in Computer Science, University of California Riverside, GPA 3.55

A.S. in Math and Science, Palomar College, San Marcos, CA

Expected June 2022 Completed June 2021

Completed June 2019

SPECIAL SKILLS:

- Proficient: C/C++, JAVA, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Shell, Object-Oriented Programming
- Previous Experience: Python, ARM, SQL databases
- Programmable & microcontroller: FPGA, ATmega1284, Raspberry Pi
- Operating Systems: Windows, MAC, Unix/Linux, Ubuntu
- Version Control & Agile tools: Git, GitHub, Trello, Visual Studio Team service
- Test: Google Test, Integration Shell Method

WORK EXPERIENCE:

UCSD Health

Software engineer Intern

July 2021-present

- Working to shift the software development process into AWS CodePipeline to a managed continuous delivery to help the team to deliver fast and reliable application and infrastructure updates.
- Working with the backend and frontend engineers on implementation of unit and integration tests using AWS CodeBuild (including continuous integration service) and AWS CodeCommit (for version control).

Best Buy, Riverside, CA

June 2019-present

Computer Sales

- Assisted customers in finding the right item, and provide recommendations on products
- Worked with the team to reach the company goals and department sales projection
- Made daily sales plan to increased customer retention/new sales by 15%

Fry's electronics, San Marcos, CA

Computer sales supervisor

Jun 2015-June 2019

- Assigned daily tasks to sales associates and follow up with them to get high standard results.
- Trained associate to achieve company sales projection by recommending and sales high margin product to costumers and offered company protection plan (performance service contract) to increase sales by 20%.
- Trained new associates on sales techniques and products functionality to reduced sales time by 12%

Certificate/Awards/relevant projects:

AWS Cloud Technical Essentials

Completion Certificate for AWS Cloud Technical Essentials from Coursera

Jul 2021

MVP Awards Jan 2019

• Received the most valuable player from Best Buy manager as a person who had the best teamwork.

Multi-Player Blackjack

- Worked in a team of two to design and implement a multiplayer blackjack web application in which players can create private/public rooms or join existing rooms from the room list. In this web application, people can interact with each other through a chatbox, and invite their friends by sharing the room's unique ID.
- The front-end was designed and implemented using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. The backend is done using MySQL, Nodejs, and PHP. https://htmcasino.net

FishHub

• As a side project, I came up with the idea to design and create a product to easily manage and control a fish tank. FishHub is a phone app written in dart language as the frontend to communicate with the backend which written in python and conducted firmware verification testing. With FishHub anyone can control any fish tank to feed, turn on/off the light, and get current temperature. Demo and GitHub

JavaToMips

- Worked in a team of two using visitor design patterns to design and implement the main phases of a modern compiler Java to Mips. The project and design contained four different parts where each part involved different requirements, design, and testing. Phases contain converting a subset of the Java language called MiniJava to simpler languages and lead to complete MIPS machine code. Completed Version
- The project designed and implemented by <u>Jens Palsberg's</u> group (UCLA) and adopted and extended by <u>Mohsen</u> Lesani.

Eight-Puzzle Solver

• Developed and wrote a program called 8-puzzle solver. The project requires using 3 search algorithms to solve the puzzle and visualize the differences between the 3 algorithms with respect to their speed. I explored the Uniform cost search, and A* searches with Misplaced Tile heuristic, and Euclidean distance heuristic by my language of choice C++. GitHub

Rshell

• Worked in a team of two using different methods of design patterns and agile methodologies to develop a shell emulator to parse and execute multiple commands and files. Conducted unit testing of each individual class with google test, and integrated testing the entire project functionality.

References

Available upon request